DAVE VON DESCHWANDEN

Full-Time Student Centennial College Taichung City, Taichung, Taiwan ROC

> 06.03.1989 Tel: 0987 903 281

Email: <u>davevond89@gmail.com</u>

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dave-von-deschwanden-a54885179/

Canadian / Swiss

PROFILE

Experienced in daily mis-en-place, menu development, inventory and working daily à la carte service and large buy-out events, banquets and weddings (fine-dining, contemporary cuisine)

Adept in effectively and calmly managing pressure under stressful situations

Able to willingly accept and use constructive criticism as a positive motivator

Strong, capable communicator within varying environments and cultures; Fluent in English, German, Intermediate Chinese, Intermediate Japanese

Management experience in both small/large scale business environments; development and handling of time sensitive product, implementation of critical strategies and leadership of employees emphasizing team building, moral and efficiency

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATES

2022 – Current Software Engineering Technology Centennial College

2020

CS50x: Introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science and the art of programming"

Harvard University / edX.org

2013 – 2014

Diplôme de Pâtisserie

Le Cordon Bleu Culinary Arts Institute Ottawa

2013

Smart Serve

Loyalist College

2013

TESOL Certificate of Educational Studies

Coventry house International – Ontesol

2013

TEYL Certificate Teaching English to Young Learners

Coventry house International – Ontesol

WORK HISTORY

2020.08 – Present Co-Owner

Bloom 14K Gold Filled Jewellery - Taichung, Taiwan

- Founded and Managed Gold-filled Jewellery business in Taiwan
- Partook in front-end side, dealing with customers and sales
- Continue to design and create jewellery ranging from necklaces, bracelets and earrings

2020.08 – *Present*Private Culinary Consultant

Taichung, Taiwan

- Consult project managers, investors, business owners and chef in helping in the streamline and efficacy of both existing businesses or start up projects
- Have worked with businesses dealing in French Cuisine, bakeries and granola manufacturing.

2016.09 – 2019.11 Chef de Partie Patisserie

mana Boulangerie - Taichung, Taiwan

- FOH and BOH duties; Daily Prep, mis-en-place, catering, weddings, custom cakes and desserts. Menu planning for weekly/monthly and seasonal changes. Doing inventory, taking deliveries, doing offsite events and cleaning
- European cakes, Pastry, Viennoiserie, savoury cuisine

2014.03 – 2015.11 Chef de Partie Patisserie

(Pastry, Garde Manger Froid / Chaud, Entremets, Grillier)

*Restaurant E18teen - Ottawa, Ontario

- Mis-en-Place, daily prep, dinner service, special events, banquets, weddings and off-sites and buy-outs, FOH brunch/late night service stations
- French / Canadian Fine Dining Restaurant (CAA four diamond; 175 seats / plus standing reception to 250)
- Smaller, well co-ordinated team producing the highest standard possible
- Undertook Inventory, arranging schedules for BOH cooks, doing deep cleans, placing weekly orders from meat/produce/Seafood and Dairy suppliers

2014.01 – 2014.06 Commis

(Garde Manger Chaud/Froid, Pastry)

Sidedoor Contemporary Kitchen & Bar - Ottawa, Ontario

- Mis-en-Place, daily prep, service prep, dinner service, special events, banquets, weddings and off-sites. Cleaning and Depp Cleaning
- Contemporary Southeast Asian/Mesoamerican Cuisine; (250 seats / 350 standing reception)
- Delivering consistent, high quality food for an average of 200 covers nightly.
- Focus on sourcing the best, organic produce from local suppliers around the Ottawa Valley and Quebec area.

2013.10 - 2014.02

Pastry Commis

Izakaya - Ottawa, Ontario

- Mis-en-Place, daily prep, service prep, dinner service, off-sites, cleaning
- Undertook Pastry Mis-En-Place moving from Prep, to eventually working dinner service and garde manger Froid / Chaud
- Contemporary Japanese Izakaya Dining; 60-80 Daily Covers

2013.10 – 2014.02 Pastry Commis

(Confiserie, Chocolaterie, Patisserie) *Stubbe Chocolates* - Ottawa, Ontario

- Daily Mis-en-Place, Baking, Chocolate/Bon-bons, Viennoiserie
- Traditional German "Konditorei" Heavy focus on cakes and Chocolate work